John A. Benjamin Papers Addendum Biomed.0001A
UCLA Library Special Collections
John A. Benjamin Papers Addendum
1895-1993
UCLA Library Special Collections
Benjamin, John A. (John Allison), 1906-
Biomed.0001A
0.5 Linear Feet (1 document box)
Letters, photographs, memorabilia, and personal records that supplement the materials in UCLA Biomedical Library's Manuscript Collection #1: "John A. Benjamin papers, 1925-1994".
Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942357433606533
Acquisition Information
In August, 2004, John A. Benjamin, son of the original collector, deposited with the UCLA Biomedical Library an additional small box of letters, photographs, and a scrapbook to be integrated into the main collection of Benjamin papers previously donated to the library.
Biography
Biographical data on Dr. Benjamin can be found in the introductory material to the finding aid for "John A. Benjamin Papers", which is available online.
Scope and Content
This addendum consists mostly of personal items and photographs. Some materials pertain to Dr. Benjamin's interest in the history of urology and medicine, but almost nothing is added to the record of his research or clinical work.
The series-subseries organization of the original large collection has been retained, but only those categories for which there are new materials are listed here.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Early Study and Research.. 2 folders
Series 2. Research, Teaching, Patient Care -- Urogenital System.. 2 folders
Series 3. Research -- Historical and Bibliographic.. 5 folders
Series 6. Personal Materials.. 5 folders
Series 7. Non-Print Materials.. 7 folders
Related Material
UCLA BIOMEDICAL LIBRARY HISTORY AND SPECIAL COLLECTIONS FOR THE SCIENCES. Manuscript Collection #1: "John A. Benjamin papers".
Urology - history; Urology; Benjamin, John A. (John Allison), 1906-
- Early Study and Research., Series 1.; 2 folders
  - Rockefeller Foundation internship., 1933, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    evaluation of the 1933 Rockefeller interns (including Benjamin) and the general program, by North Carolina State Board of Health member, 1933; correspondence between J. A. Benjamin (son) and Rockefeller Univ., 1993
  - School of Medicine graduation day, The Johns Hopkins University., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    copy of remarks made by Professor Jacob H. Hollander to President Ames, plus cover letter from Prof. Hollander to Benjamin
- Research, Teaching, Patient Care -- Urogenital System., Series 2.; 2 folders
  - Professional memberships., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    certificate of membership in The Society for Pediatric Urology
  - X-ray cinematography. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    five short 8mm film strips of dog and human bladder during urination, with enlarged photo positives
- Research -- Historical and Bibliographic., Series 3.; 5 folders
  - History of Urology., 1895-1911; Subseries 1.; 2 folders
    - American Association of Genito-Urinary Surgeons., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      memorabilia which belonged to Dr. van der Poel, from the 25th Anniversary Dinner of the Association, 1911
    - History of x-ray cinematography., 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      photo of letter from Dr. John Macintyre, Glasgow, to Prof. Röntgen, 1896; photo of first page of Röntgen article "Ueber eine neue Art von Strahlen", 1895
  - History of Medicine and Medical Books., Subseries 2.; 3 folders
    - Illustrations of historical figures. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      portraits of: Bartholin, Erasmus, 1625-1698; Bartholin, Thomas, 1616-1680; Bullein, William, d. 1576; Cheselden, William, 1688-1752; Denonvilliers, Charles-Pierre, 1808-1872; Harvey, William, 1578-1657; Pattison, Granville Sharp, 1791-1851
    - Letter from M. F. Ashley Montagu., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      concerns Benjamin's admiration of Montagu's book about Edward Tyson
    - Bozzini, Philipp. "Der Lichtleiter"., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      photocopy of a partial plate from the 1807 folio edition, with notes on the verso concerning Bozzini and Dr. Benjamin's acquisition of this work
- Personal Materials., Series 6.; 5 folders
  - Elementary and high school records, Salmon, Idaho., 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    report cards, promotion certificates from 6th grade through high school graduation
  - University of California, Southern Branch records., 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    report cards, transcript; fee receipts
  - Scrapbook., 1934-1941; 8.25" x 11.5", hard cover, loose-leaf; very brittle (Box 1, Folder 12)
    miscellaneous items, including some correspondence, newspaper and magazine clippings, poetry, etc.
    General note
    USE PHOTOCOPY (next folder) INSTEAD OF ORIGINAL
  - Scrapbook., 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    photocopy
  - Membership certificates., 1980, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    UCLA Alumni Association, 1980; The Johns Hopkins Associates, 1982
- Non-Print Materials., Series 7.; 7 folders
  - Photographs., Subseries 1.; 7 folders
    - Identified portraits. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Elmer Belt, 1893-1980 and George Whipple, 1878-1976; Campeti, Frank L.; Graham, James, 6th Duke of Montrose, 1878-1954; Hinman, Frank Jr., 1920-1999; Macintyre, John, 1859-1928; Ramsey, George H.S., 1894-1965; Scott, John; Thomson, William, 1st Baron Kelvin (Lord Kelvin), 1824-1907; Watson, James Sibley Jr., 1894-1982; Weinberg, Sydney A., 1910-1977; 35mm slides of Graham, Kelvin, Macintyre, Scott; 16mm film frames of "Early x-ray photo of soft tissue, 1896" by John Macintyre
    - Unidentified portraits. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      three photographs of men
    - Group pictures: The Johns Hopkins University., circa 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      four photographs, two negatives
      identified are John Eckert and Dave Sprong; Dr. Benjamin appears in all photographs
    - "Phi Chi at Hopkins"., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      group photograph, including Dr. Benjamin
    - Group pictures: Strong Memorial Hospital, Rochester, New York., 1943, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      four photographs, circa 1943, including Surgical Staff and Senior Staff; four photographs, circa 1957, 1967, 1969, 1970, of Urology Group
      identified in one group: Larry Parlow, Harry Miller, Don McDonald, W. W. Scott, Irwin Frank, Herbert Boyd, Abe Crockett; Dr. Benjamin in all photos
    - Annual meeting, American Urological Association, New York., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      banquet group photo of Mrs. Mae Benjamin, Dr. Benjamin, Sandor Wax, Sid Feder, Dabney Jarman, and three unidentified men
    - Dr. Benjamin and pediatric patient., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Dr. Benjamin in surgical scrubs
      RESTRICTED